Changiz Rezvani ((B.Sc., M.Sc.))

Strongly skilled and experienced VB / C# .Net Developer with vast knowledge of a variety of computer languages. Adept at all aspects of web, coding and technical support. Able to communicate technical work, accessibly, to executive-level decision makers.

PERSONAL DETAILS					
Last Employer	APM Global / MES Engineering Ltd				
Last Job Title	.Net Application Developer				
Qualifications	M.Sc. in Computer Machine Intelligence M.Sc. in Digital Electronics & Computing B.Sc. in Computer System Engineering				
Technical Skills	VB.Net/C#/.Net/OOPS Visual Studio (2017/2019)				
	ASP.Net/ SQL/Database				
	HTML 5/CSS 3.0/CMS Windows10/Office 365				
Reason for Leaving	End of Contract				
Desired Salary	£200 - £300 per day contract				
	£40k - £50k permanent				
Available	Immediately				

MISCELLANEOUS DETAILS	
LinkedIn	http://www.linkedin.com/in/changiz- rezvani/
Website:	http://www.changiz2014.biz/More
Mobile:	+44-7541-308886
Email	changiz.rezvani@gmail.com

Changiz Rezvani (B.Sc., M.Sc.)

Changiz Rezvani (B.Sc., M.Sc.) Software Developer/ Web Designer / Freelance Programmer

I am a versatile and self-motivated, software development professional with over <u>20 years</u> of top-notch experience in quality software development, object-oriented programming, overall system design, database implementation and web design. My core competencies include code development, object-oriented design, website design & development, technical and user documentations, software maintenance and some project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Software development:** Visual Studio 2019/2017, .Net Framework 4.5/4.7, C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET, WinForms, WebForms, DevExpress 18.1.6,
- **Software maintenance**: MZTools 8.0, Jetbrains ReSharper, MS Productivity Power Tools and above all Extensive Experience of Code Debugging and Code Refactoring
- Web Design: Iron Speed CMS, T-SQL, HTML 5, CSS 3.0 and JavaScript 2.0
- Windows OS: Windows 10/MS Office 365/Outlook/Adobe Acrobat/Microsoft Edge
- Project Management: Managed junior coders

KEY SKILLS

- Demonstrated a strong ability to analyse & solve problems
- Track record of successfully handling multiple projects all at the same time
- Proven track record of developing creative strategies
- Excellent knowledge of programming and IT both general and in detail
- Able to work effectively with superiors, peers, and subordinates
- Project a self-confident, authoritative but friendly and enthusiastic personality
- Extremely versatile in providing help and support for others in their work
- Track record of developing positive working relationships
- Make a favourable impression and easily gains acceptance of others
- Able to, fairly and effectively, work as part of a team
- For the past 5 years, continually updating & upgrading my marketable skills with Lynda.com my favourite training website

ACADEMIC EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

M.Sc. in Computer Machine Intelligence M.Sc. in Digital Electronics & Computing B.Sc. in Computer System Engineering A-Levels Math (Pure &Applied) & Physics University of Surrey University of Kent University off Kent London F.E. College

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

August 2020 - Now (remote collaboration)

- Converted my previous employer's application, PLASMA, to run seamlessly on cloud inside the Azure VM.
 Nov 2020
- Converted my previous employer's application, PLASMA 's 75,000-line VB.Net code, to C# in less than two
 months Sep 2020.
- Remotely developed, in less than three days, a sample test driven solution in C#, as part of requirement for a job interview Sep 2020.

May 2017 - Sep. 2017

Had a short gap in the employment and travelled abroad for business purposes.

September 2012 - May 2020 (ongoing fixed term contracts)

MES International Ltd / APM Global (currently in dispute over product ownership with MES)

MES is an innovative and multidisciplinary consulting company providing services in the Energy, Chemical and Process industries.

- Secured a contract for the re-designing of MES in-house software now called PLASMA + from ground up for creating a cloud-based version of the software - http://mes-international.biz/PlasmaDoc/
- Built an <u>Employees Tracker Project</u> a software package that helps employees submitting their time sheets
 online and the managers to budget the company expenses accordingly ASP.Net/SQL/JS/HTML/CSS/ISD CMS
- Plasma Project A commercial desktop engineering application extensively used by BP and other similar oil and gas companies for plant simulation, coded in VB.Net/C#/VB6
- Supervised the junior programmer(s) for them to upgrade MES' VB6 software to .Net VB.Net/C#
- AMNIS project a software developed specifically for the oil and gas industry with the purpose of assessing the safety of the plants. I was extensively involved upgrading and improving the earlier code VB.Net
- Preparing lectures as well as presentations, about the progress of the project MS-Office/Flip HTML
- Created an online manual online interactive software manual for PLASMA Robo Help/ HTML

May 2009 – July 2012

GPMT Ltd, London, Software Developer/Information Architect

Designed, managed and upgraded the company's bullion trading website using ASP.Net/SQL/JS/HTML/CSS

May 2000 - July 2008

Sim. Eng. Ltd, Leatherhead, Software Developer and Programmer

Designed and programmed the company's desktop simulation software using VB6

SELECTED ACHIEVEMENTS

- Continued with upgrading of <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling software</u> in .Net for APM Global, Jul 2019 - Now (As <u>business partner</u> until the court case against MES is settled)
- Continued with upgrading of <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling software</u> in .Net for MES International, Jan 2019 – Apr 2019 (self-employed)
- Continued with upgrading of <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling software</u> in .Net for MES International, July 2018 – December 2018 (fixed term contract)
- Travelled abroad on business, as well as worked as freelancer on various Web and Software projects,
 May 2017 Sep 2018
- Designed and extensively upgraded <u>Plant Simulation and Modelling software</u> in .Net for MES International, 2014 – 2017
- Created an <u>Online Job Tracking and Asset Management software</u> for MES International,
 2014 2015 Login using id: <u>changiz2008@gmail.com & pwd:</u> plasma123456
- Re-coded and extended Safety and Risk Analysis software for MES, 2012 2013
- Designed an Online Trading Website for the Precious Metal Trading Company, GMPT, 2009 2012
- Coded Plant Simulation and Modelling software for Sim. Eng. in VB6 and VB.Net, 2000 2008

Changiz Rezvani (B.Sc., M.Sc.)

RECENT TRAINING - LinkedIn Learning | Career Match UK

- A variety of LinkedIn courses available, for free, to public due to the recent Corona pandemic
- Azure, crash course online, as we are planning in moving our software to cloud, Oct 2020
- Computer Networking, a crash course online by Google, Sep 2020
- System Administration, a crash course online by Google, Sep 2020
- Started P/T A+ training with Career Match, May 2020
- Registered and started various online courses with Allison, Mar 2020
- SEO Optimisation workshop with Ravenscourt university, Greenwich, London, Feb 2020
- Digital Marketing and SEO Optimisation with New Skills Academy, April 2019
- Advanced C#/.Net Programming/Responsive Web Design/Project Management & Other IT related topics at LinkedIn Learning aka Lynda.com
- HTML 5.0 | CSS 3.0 | JavaScript | ASP.Net | A+ <u>certifications</u> & Other IT related stuff at Career Match UK –
 2017
- Business, Technology, IT Skills certifications & Various other IT & business-related courses at Lynda.com 2014-2017

Foreign Languages

- Italian
- Turkish
- Farsi

References available upon request

Appendix 1

Breakdown of my flagship project, PLASMA, since year 2000 in VB6 and then since 2012 in VB.Net

Project	Description	Maintainability Index	Cyclomatic Complexity	Depth of Inheritance	Class Coupling	Lines of Code
Mes.Plasma.Report	Creates a PDF report of the Plasma Items	72	111	7	102	380
Mes.Plasma.FileRW	Saves Plasma data and graph on disk	85	238	7	72	630
Mes.Plasma.Database	Records the Plasma Items in a database grid	67	299	1	29	1334
Mes.Plasma.Global	Provides generic procedures for the other modules	77	823	1	44	1604
Mes.Plasma.Charts	Shows simulation results as charts on the screen	73	840	13	261	3378
Mes.Plasma.Simulation	Performs graph tracing and finds out the results of simulating what is on display on the screen	62	3070	10	123	10472
Mes.Plasma.MDI	Implements the MDI frame of the overall software	68	7222	12	939	25374
Mes.Plasma.Draw	Supports the Graph drawing and the display of all the screen items of Plasma	68	12669	10	530	34138
	*				Total:	77310

PLASMA project's dependency graph

